the3day.org 2009-12-21

# Welcome to the Susan G. Komen 3-Day for the Cure: Privacy Policy

The Breast Cancer 3-Day (“we” or “us” or “our”) is committed to responsible information handling practices. You can visit most pages on our site (hereinafter defined) without giving us any information about yourself, but sometimes we need information to provide information or services that you request. This Privacy Policy explains data collection and use in those situations. By visiting our web site, you consent to the information practices described in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy applies to our web site, which is located at the URL [www.The3Day.org](http://www.the3day.org/) (and each sub-domain associated with this URL) (collectively, the “Site”). This Privacy Policy does not apply to other sites that may be accessible through the Site. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of persons or entities that the Breast Cancer 3-Day does not control, manage or employ. The Site contains links to other sites that are operated by third parties, including, but not limited to, third party sites that may display the name, trademarks, service marks and logos of the Breast Cancer 3-Day. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of those other sites to learn how they collect and use information about you.

In order to fully understand your rights, we encourage you to read this Privacy Policy as well as our [Terms of Use](http://www.the3day.org/site/PageServer?pagename=termsofuse). The Breast Cancer 3-Day reserves the right at any time and without notice to change this Privacy Policy simply by posting such changes on the Site. Any such change will be effective immediately upon posting. 

To assist you with reading through our Privacy Policy, we have provided answers to questions that you may find most important:

[What type of information does the Breast Cancer 3-Day COLLECT and how is the information USED?](http://www.the3day.org/site/PageServer?pagename=privacypolicy#privacy1)  
[Does the Breast Cancer 3-Day use COOKIES, OTHER TECHNOLOGIES or THIRD PARTIES to INDIRECTLY collect information on the Site?](http://www.the3day.org/site/PageServer?pagename=privacypolicy#privacy2)  
[Does the Breast Cancer 3-Day SHARE the information that I have provided or that has been collected?](http://www.the3day.org/site/PageServer?pagename=privacypolicy#privacy3)  
[Do I have CHOICES regarding how my Personal Information is used?](http://www.the3day.org/site/PageServer?pagename=privacypolicy#privacy4)  
[How does the Breast Cancer 3-Day SECURE my Personal Information?](http://www.the3day.org/site/PageServer?pagename=privacypolicy#privacy15)  
[Does the Breast Cancer 3-Day collect Personal Information from CHILDREN?](http://www.the3day.org/site/PageServer?pagename=privacypolicy#privacy8)  
[If I give the Breast Cancer 3-Day the name and email address of my family or friends, how is that information used?](http://www.the3day.org/site/PageServer?pagename=privacypolicy#privacy9)  
[Whom can I CONTACT if I have questions or concerns about the Privacy Policy?](http://www.the3day.org/site/PageServer?pagename=privacypolicy#privacy11)  

**What type of information does the Breast Cancer 3-Day COLLECT and how is the information USED?  
**  
While you are visiting the Site, the Breast Cancer 3-Day may collect two types of information about users: “Personal Information” (such as name, email address, mailing address, phone, credit card or debit card, personal preferences and other account-related information) and “Aggregate Information” (such as information about how many users log on to the Site on a daily basis). 

Personal Information is collected online when you voluntarily submit non-public personal information on the Site by requesting information, purchasing our products, signing up for an account or other services, receiving electronic notices or other similar communications and other similar activities. 

Aggregate Information is non-personally identifiable/anonymous information about you, such as pages most frequently accessed by you, time spent on a page or area of the Site, the number of visits to the Site by you, types of browser used by you, cookie preferences or search terms entered by you. 

Aggregate Information is used in a collective manner, and no single person can be identified by that compiled information (for example, the number of people who logged into the Site in a particular day). Aggregate Information does not personally identify a specific user. 

_Personal Information That You Provide to Us  
_  
We may obtain Personal Information about you ONLY if you elect to give us that information. Types of   
Personal Information may include the following:

  * Name 
  * Address 
  * Zip code 
  * Telephone number 
  * Occupation 
  * Email address 
  * Credit card number and expiration date (for online purchases or donations) 
  * Name of organization (where applicable)
  * Breast cancer survivor or relationship to a breast cancer survivor

We may request Personal Information, such as your user name or password, whenever you login to your account and may in limited circumstances ask you to provide credit card information and other personal information when making a donation online or registering for a Breast Cancer 3-Day. We reserve the right to request any additional information necessary to establish and maintain your account. Generally, our uses of Personal Information collected online include, without limitation, responding to your inquiry about volunteering time to the Breast Cancer 3-Day, enabling you to make a donation, or providing information, such as sending marketing communications and newsletters. 

The Breast Cancer 3-Day will retain your Personal Information for fulfillment of the intended purposes for which such Personal Information is collected. The Breast Cancer 3-Day will establish minimum and maximum retention periods based upon the type of information collected (i.e., sensitivity), the intended purposes and as otherwise may be legally required. 

Personal Information shall NOT include any personal information posted or sent by or to you in any public forum (such as a message board) or any participant personal fundraising webpage on the Site. Participation in these public forums and the Breast Cancer 3-Day fundraising initiatives requires the public release and dissemination of such information, and thus the Breast Cancer 3-Day cannot commit to treating such information confidentially in the same manner that other personal information will be treated under this Privacy Policy. Participation in these programs is voluntary and thus your consent to certain terms is required before participation is allowed. 

_Aggregate Information Collected Automatically  
_  
When you visit the Site, we automatically collect Aggregate Information about your visit. We can tell the type of computer, browser, and web service that you are using. We also know the date, time, and pages that you visit. Collecting this information helps us design the Site to enhance your experience while on our Site. 

The Breast Cancer 3-Day also may use Aggregate Information for internal purposes, such as tracking demographic data and providing targeted content to make the Site more useful to our visitors. The gathering of this Aggregate Information may be accomplished by the use of cookies or web beacons by the Breast Cancer 3-Day and its third party service providers. In particular, the Breast Cancer 3-Day will collect an IP Address from all visitors to the Site. An IP Address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. The Breast Cancer 3-Day may share Aggregate Information with its content providers, sponsors, service providers or other third parties to advance the goals of research, education, dissemination of information and otherwise in fulfillment of the Breast Cancer 3-Day mission to raise funds for breast cancer research, education, and community health programs. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Site, analyze trends, track users’ movement on the Site, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the Site, and deliver customized, personalized content. IP addresses, however, are not linked to Personal Information. The Breast Cancer 3-Day also may use an unique assigned number located with the Site’s URL to determine the web site from which you navigated to get to the Site. While this number may not be apparent to you, it does not contain your Personal Information.

**Does the Breast Cancer 3-Day use COOKIES, OTHER TECHNOLOGIES or THIRD PARTIES to INDIRECTLY collect information on the Site?  
**  
The Site may use cookies to enhance your experience while using the Site. Cookies are pieces of information that some web sites transfer to the computer that is browsing that site and are used for record-keeping purposes at many web sites. Use of cookies makes web-surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving your passwords, your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular web site and to make sure you do not see the same ad repeatedly. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard. 

Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our Site will not function properly when you view them. 

The Site also may use other technologies to track the specific pages viewed by visitors on the Site or to target specific content that might be of interest to you. These technologies help us to understand how visitors use the Site. However, you will have the option to opt out (or opt in if applicable law requires) of receiving such targeted content on those pages on our Site where this technology is used.

**Does the Breast Cancer 3-Day SHARE the information that I have provided or that has been collected?  
**  
The Breast Cancer 3-Day may need to share Personal Information with third parties in limited circumstances. For example, we may release Personal Information to third parties to perform services such as advising you of our upcoming events, products, volunteer opportunities, fundraising and partner-related product opportunities benefiting the Breast Cancer 3-Day or its beneficiaries, providing you with breast health/breast cancer information or processing credit card payments or hosting the Site (and/or features available on the Site). However, such third parties are obligated to maintain the confidentiality of Personal Information and are not authorized to use Personal Information for any purpose other than providing those services.

From time to time, we may be required to provide Personal Information or Aggregate Information in response to a valid court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law, or if we reasonably believe that you have committed unlawful acts or acts that may endanger the health or safety of another user or the general public. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may release certain personal information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of others and ourselves. 

We also reserve the right to share, assign or transfer your Personal information to any of our beneficiaries or any successor in interest to our organization by merger, reorganization, or operation of law.

In addition, the Breast Cancer 3-Day may make your name and postal address available to other non-profit organizations whose services or activities may be of interest to you.

**Do I have CHOICES regarding how my Personal Information is used?**

The Breast Cancer 3-Day may make your name and postal address available to other nonprofit organizations whose services or activities may be of interest to you. If you would like to opt out of having the Breast Cancer 3-Day share your name and postal address with those organizations, please [log in to our website](http://www.the3day.org/site/UserLogin) and update your profile. If you do not know your username and password, [click here](http://www.the3day.org/site/UserLogin).

If your Personal Information is currently being used by the Breast Cancer 3-Day or its beneficiaries to send you marketing communications, you can opt out at any time. All marketing email communications from the Breast Cancer 3-Day tell you how to stop receiving them; however, to opt out of receiving marketing communications from the Breast Cancer 3-Day:

  1. [Log in to our website](http://www.the3day.org/site/UserLogin) and update your profile or
  2. Follow directions on a marketing email communication from us; or
  3. Send a request by email to: [coaches@the3day.org](mailto:coaches@the3day.org "E-mail coaches@the3day.org"). (Please reference this Privacy Policy in your subject line.)

The Breast Cancer 3-Day has made available the public forums on the Site (including the Breast Cancer 3-Day Message Board) so that you may have an opportunity to interact with other Site visitors in order to share knowledge and news or participate in fundraising events benefiting the Breast Cancer 3-Day and its beneficiaries. Since participation in such forums is voluntary, you control what personal information may be disclosed to others. In order to avoid your email address or other personal information from being gathered and used by others for unsolicited, inappropriate or harmful purposes, the Breast Cancer 3-Day advises that you should be cautious about posting your email address or phone number or other personal information to newsgroups, blogs, message boards, or other public forums. In addition, access to Personal Information contained in your account is protected by use of a password so keep your password private and secure. 

**What are the terms of the Breast Cancer 3-Day Message Board?  
**  
The Message Board administrator reserves the right to remove, edit, move or close any topic at any time. We also reserve the right to disallow or ban users from posting. If responding to a post, please limit your response to comments directly related to the original comment or question. Please post only under the appropriate topic as described. Your post may be removed if you do not follow these instructions.

While the administrators and moderators of the forum will attempt to remove or edit any objectionable material as quickly as possible, it is impossible to review every message. Therefore, all posts made express the views and opinions of the author only and not of the Breast Cancer 3-Day, or its beneficiaries, sponsors or the administrator.

By participating, each user agrees not to post any abusive, anonymous, obscene, vulgar, slanderous, hateful, threatening, sexually-oriented or any other material that may violate any applicable laws. Doing so may lead you to being immediately and permanently banned (and your service provider being informed). The IP address of all posts is recorded to aid in enforcing these conditions.

**How can I UPDATE or CHANGE my Personal Information?  
**  
The Breast Cancer 3-Day wants your account (including without limitation, your Personal Information and preferences) to be accurate and complete. To update or change your Personal Information, visit our user login page and log on to your own account. You can update your Personal Information after logging in to your account. You also can send your updated Personal Information by email to: [coaches@the3day.org](mailto:coaches@the3day.org "E-mail coaches@the3day.org"). (Please reference this Privacy Policy in your subject line.)  

**How does the Breast Cancer 3-Day SECURE my Personal Information?  
**  
The Breast Cancer 3-Day maintains commercially reasonable safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the Personal Information provided by you. Such security safeguards are intended to be appropriate to the sensitivity of the Personal Information collected. To the extent the Breast Cancer 3-Day transfers any Personal Information to third parties, the Breast Cancer 3-Day will use commercially reasonable efforts to assure that such third parties to whom it may transfer any Personal Information have knowledge of this Privacy Policy and provide sufficient protection of such Personal Information. In particular, the Breast Cancer 3-Day requires that a secure session be established using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) and Secure Electronic Transaction (SET) protocol when you submit Personal Information to us through your use of the Site to establish an account, use the shopping cart, input credit card or debit card information for payment, and access certain web pages on the Site. Additionally, the Breast Cancer 3-Day utilizes digital certificates issued by VeriSign, an established signer of digital certificates.

The Breast Cancer 3-Day is committed to properly securing the Personal Information collected online. To help us accomplish this, we take the following steps:

  * We employ internal access controls to ensure that the only people who see your information are those with a need to do so to perform their official duties.
  * We train relevant personnel on our privacy and security measures.
  * We physically secure the areas where we hold hard copies of the information that we collect online.
  * We regularly back up the information that we collect online to insure against loss. 
  * We use technical controls to secure the information that we collect online as appropriate, including but not limited to: Secure Socket Layer (SSL), encryption, firewalls, and password protections.
  * We periodically test our security procedures to ensure personnel and technical compliance.

Please note that Personal Information stored on the Site will be collected, stored and processed in the United States of America. By this Privacy Policy, the Breast Cancer 3-Day has intended to abide by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of data from the European Union and the PIPEDA regarding the collection, use and retention of data from Canada.   

**Does the Breast Cancer 3-Day collect Personal Information from CHILDREN?  
**  
Since the Site is not designed specifically for children, the Breast Cancer 3-Day does not intentionally collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If we discover that we have inadvertently collected Personal Information from a person under the age of 13, we will automatically delete it.  

**If I give the Breast Cancer 3-Day the name and email address of my family or friends, how is that information used?**

If you elect to use any features of the Site (such as “Tell A Friend”) to inform a friend about the Site or solicit donations or pledges or otherwise communicate, the Breast Cancer 3-Day may ask for your friend’s name and email address. The Site will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the Site. The Breast Cancer 3-Day will store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. Your friend may contact the Breast Cancer 3-Day to request the removal of this information from our databases.

**What are the terms of the Breast Cancer 3-Day Share List?  
**  
The Share List is a list of participants who have chosen to share their contact information with other participants for the purpose of forming training and support groups. The share list is sorted by U.S. zip code. A maximum of 50 results are returned for any one search, and will only include participants who have opted to put their information on this list. This list is not intended for solicitation of any kind or for communication unrelated to the Breast Cancer 3-Day. The Breast Cancer 3-Day, in its sole discretion, may ban a user from accessing this share list if such user is deemed to have abused it. 

**Whom can I CONTACT if I have questions or concerns about the Privacy Policy?  
**  
The Breast Cancer 3-Day has designated a Privacy Manager who can be contacted at the Breast Cancer 3-Day contact address listed at the end of this Privacy Policy. Our Privacy Manager is accountable for the Breast Cancer 3-Day’s online compliance with this Privacy Policy. If you have questions about our Privacy Policy or if you have a claim concerning our compliance with this Privacy Policy, you can email our Privacy Manager at [coaches@the3day.org](mailto:coaches@the3day.org "E-mail coaches@the3day.org"). Please reference this Privacy Policy in your subject line, and please provide a description of your claims or questions in sufficient detail so as to permit our Privacy Manager to investigate your claims or questions fully and contact you. It is our intent to make available to you through our Privacy Manager specific information about this Privacy Policy and our management of your Personal Information as may be required by applicable law.   

**Will this Privacy Policy CHANGE?  
**  
Since the Site will continue to implement new technologies and improve the services and features, this Privacy Policy is subject to change. If there are changes or additions to this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes here or in other formats that we deem acceptable, so that you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it and what choices you have.  

**What constitutes my acceptance of this Privacy Policy?  
**  
By using the Site, you expressly consent to the use and disclosure of information as described in this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the Site after the effective date of any modification to the Privacy Policy will be deemed to be your agreement to the changed terms. You agree to review the Privacy Policy each time you use the Site so that you are aware of such modifications.   

**Where can I get more information about the Privacy Policy?  
**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:  
The Breast Cancer 3-Day  
800.996.3DAY (800.996.3329)

You can also send an email to: [coaches@the3day.org](mailto:coaches@the3day.org "E-mail coaches@the3day.org"). (Please reference this Privacy Policy in your subject line.)

POSTED: 04/10/2009
